<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Jakob Schwalb-Willmann</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Jakob Schwalb-Willmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year} Jakob Schwalb-Willmann</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 22:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>“An Introduction to Spatial Data Analysis” helps beginners getting started working with spatial data in QGIS and R.
Wegmann, M.; Schwalb-Willmann, J.; Dech, S. (2020). An Introduction to Spatial Data Analysis: Remote Sensing and GIS with Open Source Software. Exeter, UK. Pelagic Publishing. ISBN: 9781784272135.
Schwalb-Willmann, J.; Remelgado, R.; Safi, K.; Wegmann, M. (2020). moveVis: Animating movement trajectories in synchronicity with static or temporally dynamic environmental data in R. Methods Ecol Evol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 22:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching at the AniMove Science School 2019 at Yale University, USA
2020 Seminar “Advanced Programming for Spatial Analysis”, EAGLE MSc.: Practical training to strengthen technical and methodological skills in machine learning (deep neural networks for computer vision, deep learning, discriminative modeling), machine-to-machine communication and creating efficient local and cloud-based development environments for Python and R.
Seminar “Scientific Graphics”, EAGLE MSc.: Training to improve skills in creating scientific graphics using R and LaTeX, and communicating scientific work through web applications using shiny in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 22:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Migration of White Storks, tracked between 2011 and 2017 by the Max Planck Institute of Animal Behavior, on top of a dynamic NASA Blue Marble background representing global seasonality, animated using moveVis. Video copyright: Jakob Schwalb-Willmann  PhD Research project on the “Potentials of animal-environment interactions for remote sensing research”, supervised by Prof. Dr. Stefan Dech (Earth Observation Center at the German Aerospace Center, DLR) and Prof. Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>