<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PhD on Jakob Schwalb-Willmann</title>
    <link>/tags/phd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PhD on Jakob Schwalb-Willmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© {year} Jakob Schwalb-Willmann</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2019 PhD colloquium at DLR&#39;s Earth Observation Center (EOC) in Oberpfaffenhofen</title>
      <link>/blog/phd-colloquium-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/phd-colloquium-2019/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: This year’s attendees of our annual PhD colloquium at EOC in Oberpfaffenhofen.  Last Thursday, on November 28th, 2019, our annual PhD colloquium took place at the Earth Observation Center (EOC) at DLR in Oberpfaffenhofen. As every year, the current PhD students of Prof. Dr. Stefan Dech met to present the concepts and statuses of their PhDs and to discuss their approaches and ideas within a larger group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2018 PhD colloquium at DLR&#39;s Earth Observation Center (EOC) in Oberpfaffenhofen</title>
      <link>/blog/phd-colloquium-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/phd-colloquium-2018/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: This year’s attendees of our annual PhD colloquium at EOC in Oberpfaffenhofen.  Yesterday, on November 14th, 2018, the annual PhD colloquium of PhD candiates supervised by Prof. Dr. Stefan Dech met at the Earth Observation Center (EOC) at DLR in Oberpfaffenhofen to talk about their PhD topics and statuses. Each PhD candidate presented her or his PhD concept and status and addressed challenges and successes of the past year, followed by a discussion with the present candidates and supervisors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>